The Barcelona subway pulls into the station, the doors slide open and passengers pour out to go about their daily business.
巴塞罗那的地铁驶进车站，车门滑开，乘客们涌出车厢，去忙各自的日常事务。
Little do they know that as they do so, a burst of energy is sent up to street level to help charge an electric car.
他们根本不知道，就在他们这样做的时候，一股能量正被输送到街面上，帮一辆电动汽车充电。
Barcelona has put together a package of clean energy technologies to help public transportation go greener, while also doing its part to tackle climate change and aid Europe’s difficult shift to the privately owned electric vehicle market.
巴塞罗那整合了一整套清洁能源技术，让公共交通更环保，同时也为应对气候变化出一份力，并助力欧洲向私人电动汽车市场的艰难转型。
Sixteen stations of Barcelona’s subway system are part of its new MetroCharge project, whereby the energy from the underground trains’ brakes is used to power the trains and the stations themselves, while the remainder is sent snaking through cables to the surface to power plug-in stations for privately owned vehicles.
巴塞罗那地铁系统的16个车站加入了新的“地铁充电”项目：地下列车刹车产生的能量被用来为列车和车站本身供电，剩余部分则通过蜿蜒的电缆输送到地面，为私家车的插电式充电桩供电。
Bernardo Espinoza, an engineer who takes the subway every day, owns an electric car.
贝尔纳多·埃斯皮诺萨是一名每天乘坐地铁的工程师，他有一辆电动汽车。
“I am pleasantly surprised, because I am always looking for where to plug it in,” Espinoza said before catching the subway in a working-class area of southern Barcelona.
“我感到惊喜，因为我总是在找地方给它充电，”埃斯皮诺萨在巴塞罗那南部一个工人阶层聚居区赶地铁前说道。
“And if it is from energy from the trains’ brakes, then even better.”
“如果电来自列车刹车的能量，那就更好了。”
Regenerative brakes have been in trains for decades and are also used in some cars.
再生制动在列车上已经使用了几十年，一些汽车上也有应用。
They consist of an electric motor which collects energy used in the braking action that would be lost as heat by conventional brakes.
它们由一台电动机构成，电动机收集刹车过程中的能量，而这些能量在传统刹车中会以热量的形式散失。
That energy can be immediately used to accelerate the vehicle or, in the case of the Barcelona subway system, sent along cables to supply electricity for the station or for electric car chargers.
这些能量可以立即用来给车辆加速；或者，就巴塞罗那地铁系统而言，通过电缆输送，为车站或电动汽车充电桩供电。
Alvaro Luna, a professor of electrical engineering, said that the system is innovative in so far as it allows for recycled energy to be redirected to specific local uses — in this case powering electric cars parked nearby.
电气工程学教授阿尔瓦罗·卢纳说，这个系统的创新之处在于，它让回收的能量能够被重新引导，用于本地的特定用途——在这里就是为停在附近的电动汽车供电。
That, he said, boosts efficiency.
他说，这提高了效率。